Alexander Graham Bell Family
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Family Papers, 1834-1972, n.d. (Box 1-101)
  - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard
    - Family correspondence
      - McCurdy, Robert H.
      - McCurdy, Virginia
      - Pillot, Gertrude H. ("Gipsy")
      - Ripley, Helen Bell
      - Salisbury, Evelyn McCurdy
      - Scudder, Bessie
      - Symonds, Hetty J.
      - Symonds, Katie I.
      - Symonds, Mary E.
      - Symonds, Stanley
      - Taft, Louise
      - Wagner, Sarah Griswold See also Container 56, Marsh, Sarah Griswold
      - Copies of letters from the parents of Mabel Gardiner Hubbard Bell
      - Unidentified family letters and fragments
    - General correspondence
      - Abbott, Charles G.
      - Albert I, Prince of Monaco
      - Baldwin, Frederick W. ("Casey")
      - Barnard, Josephine Elizabeth
      - Blake, Clarence J.
      - Booth, Frank W. For additional material see Container 127, American Association to Promote the Teaching of Speech to the Deaf; Container 179, Census; Container 191, Institution for the Deaf and Dumb; and Container 201, Teachers of the deaf
      - Carty, John J. For additional material see Container 64, Death of Alexander Graham Bell (Box 59)
      - Cleveland, Frances Folsom
      - Crouter, Albert L. E.
      - Curtiss, Glenn H.
      - Deland, Fred
      - Fuller, Sarah
      - Gallaudet, Edward Miner
      - Hale, Edward Everett
      - Holmes, Henry W.
      - Keller, Helen For additional material see Containers 81-83, Biography of Alexander Graham Bell
      - Kelvin, William Thomson, Baron For additional material see Containers 81-83, Biography of Alexander Graham Bell
      - Kennan, Emeline ("Lena")
        - 1891-1899, (3 folders)
        - 1900-1914, n.d. (Box 60)
      - Kennan, George
      - Keyes, C. M.
      - Kirwan, Kate
      - Langley, Samuel P.
      - Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth For additional material see Container 133, Peirce, Benjamin
      - McCurdy, Arthur W.
      - McKenzie, Catherine
      - Mitchell, Donald Grant
      - Noyes, Frederick K.
      - Noyes, Theodore W.
      - Office of Foreign Seed and Plant Introduction
      - Peary, Robert Edwin
      - Pinchot, Gifford For additional material see Container 132, National Child Labor Committee, and Containers 326-327, Wednesday evening receptions
      - Radcliffe, F. L.
      - Sherman, John
      - Sullivan, Annie
      - Taft, Helen Herron
      - Taft, William H. (1857-1930)
      - Tarbell, Ida M.
      - Thompson, Charles
      - True, Mary H. (Box 61)
        - From, 1875-1919, n.d., (6 folders)
        - To
          - 1875-1895, (2 folders)
          - 1896-1923, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 62)
      - Unwin, Thomas Fisher
      - Watson, Elizabeth Kimball (Mrs. Thomas A. Watson)
      - Watson, Thomas A.
      - Wheeler, Benjamin Ide
      - White, Andrew Dickson
      - Yale, Caroline A. For additional material see Containers 179-180, Clarke School for the Deaf; Container 181, Ohio; Container 201, True, Mary H., Tributes to; and Container 222, Keller, Helen, Correspondence
      - Miscellaneous
        - A-M, (6 folders)
        - N-Y and unidentified, (3 folders) (Box 63)
      - Letters of condolence on death of Alexander Graham Bell
        - A-N, (4 folders)
        - O-Z (Box 64)
    - Subject file
      - Ancestry of Mabel Gardiner Hubbard Bell
      - Armistice commemoration, Baddeck, Nova Scotia, Canada
      - Biographical material, (2 folders)
      - Clarke School for the Deaf, Northampton, Mass. See Containers 179-180, same heading
      - Death of Alexander Graham Bell, funeral arrangements
      - Funeral and estate
      - Mabel Hubbard Clubs
      - Montessori
        - Bell, Alexander Graham, extracts from home notes re education
        - Coburn Players
        - Correspondence
          - A-K, (2 folders)
          - M-W, (2 folders) (Box 65)
        - Dissolution of Montessori Educational Association
        - Financial papers
        - History in the United States
        - Printed matter and clippings, (3 folders)
        - Property
      - Sewing school for girls, Baddeck, Nova Scotia, Canada (Box 66)
      - Silver replica of telephone
      - Wedding invitations
      - Young Ladies Club of Baddeck, Baddeck, Nova Scotia, Canada, (2 folders)
    - Article file
      - "Advances in Telephony", (2 folders)
      - "Alaskan Boundary Question"
      - "Alfred Tennyson"
      - "Andrea del Sarto and His Times"
      - "Australasian Oddments"
      - "Battle of the Cells"
      - "The Channel Islands"
      - "Chaucer and Spender"
      - "Christmas- Its Meaning"
      - "The Church of England Pageant"
      - "The Common House Fly"
      - "The Constitution of the U.S."
      - "Current Events"
      - "Current Topics"
      - "Dreyfus"
      - "The Dreyfus Case"
      - "Four Evenings on Village Improvement"
      - "Further contributions to the study of that Subtile Art which may inable one with an observant Eie to Heare what any man speaks by the moving lips"
      - "A Garden"
      - "General Charles P. Stone"
      - "Geoffrey Chaucer"
      - "Germany and Turkey Make Agreement"
      - "Glaciers"
      - "Grand Lands of Southwestern France"
      - "Highways of the Past"
      - "How To Live Two Hundred Years"
      - "Impressions of Queensland"
      - "The Influence of the War on Literature"
      - "Martin Luther"
      - "The Nicaragua Ship Canal"
      - "On Christmas Giving"
      - "Paris Exposition"
      - "The Peace Conference"
      - "Peace Treaty between Japan and Russia"
      - "A Prophesy"
      - "Railroads of the World"
      - "The Relation of the Medici to Michaelangelo"
      - "Reminiscing on the Lives of Three Men"
      - "Sicily"
      - "Some Reflections on Language and the Way It Is Taught"
      - "Stone Pasha"
      - "A Story"
      - "Story of a Lily"
      - "The Subtile Art of Speech Reading", (2 folders)
      - "To the Women of America, Mothers, Wives, and Daughters of Brave Men, Attention!"
      - "Transvaal"
      - "A Tribute to Mrs. Gardiner Greene Hubbard"
      - "The Use of Highways as Memorials"
      - "Waterways of Canada"
      - "Weeds"
      - "Whittier as a Poet"
      - "William Shakespeare"
      - "Wireless Telegraphy"
      - "Woman's Rights"
      - "World of Silence"
      - "The World's Fair"
      - "Yacht Races"
      - Untitled
        - 1880
        - ca. 1890-1895
        - ca. Oct. 1897
        - 1898
        - ca. 1900
        - 1905
        - Undated
      - Fragments
    - Book file (Box 68)
      - Autobiography, unpublished, 1923
      - Biography of Gardiner Greene Hubbard, incomplete
    - Lecture file
      - Trip to Japan, 1898
    - Playscript file
      - Just an Incident
    - Poetry file, n.d.
    - Speech file
      - "Christopher Columbus"
      - "Government vs. Private Ownership"
      - "Housekeeping--Making a Chore Interesting"
      - "Immigration of Humans"
      - "Margot Asquith and Her Book"
      - "Weather"
      - Untitled
        - 1891, Oct. 10
        - ca. 1892
        - 1893, Oct. 11
        - 1894, Feb. 28
        - ca. 1895
        - 1914, Nov. 30
        - Undated
    - Miscellany (Box 69)
      - Account book
      - Calendar of quotations
      - Cancelled checks
      - Cards, wedding invitations, etc.
      - Certificates
      - Financial papers, trusts, estate papers, and codicil to will, (2 folders)
      - Fragmentary recollections of Mary True
      - Itinerary for western trip
      - Lists and notes, (2 folders)
      - Medical report
      - Monograms and monogram book
      - Notebook
      - Notebook on visible speech (Box 70)
      - Nursery rhymes for Little Scientists
      - Sketch by Mabel Gardiner Hubbard Bell, 1874
  - Bell, Melville James
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Alexander Graham
    - Miscellany
      - Articles, birth certificate, and engraving on tombstone
  - Bell, Robert
  - Blatchford, Carrie
  - Blatchford, Mary
  - Fairchild, Alexander Graham Bell
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Alexander Graham
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard
  - Fairchild, Barbara
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Alexander Graham
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard
  - Fairchild, David
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Alexander Graham
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard, 1904-1920, n.d., (3 folders)
      - Fairchild, Marian ("Daisy") (Box 71)
      - Grosvenor, Gilbert Hovey
    - General correspondence
      - Booth, Frank W. For additional material see Container 127, American Association to Promote the Teaching of Speech to the Deaf; Container 179, Census; Container 191, Institution for the Deaf and Dumb; and Container 201, Teachers of the deaf
      - Crouter, Albert L. E.
      - Davidson, John G.
      - Deland, Fred
      - Fuller, Sarah
      - Sargent, Charles S.
      - Miscellaneous, A-W
    - Miscellany
      - Financial papers and notes
  - Fairchild, Marian ("Daisy")
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Alexander Graham
      - Bell, Caroline Ottoway ("Carrie")
      - Bell, Eliza Symonds
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard
        - 1881-1897, (2 folders)
        - 1898-1920, (8 folders) (Box 72)
        - 1921-1922, n.d., (4 folders) (Box 73)
      - Coleman, Frances Fairchild
      - Fairchild, Agnes
      - Fairchild, Anna W.
      - Fairchild, Edwin A.
      - Fairchild, Graham
      - Fairchild, Salome Cutler
      - Grossman, Gertrude Hubbard
      - Grosvenor, Asa W.
      - Grosvenor, Elsie Bell
      - Hubbard, Edith
      - Hubbard, F. Tracy
      - Hubbard, Gertrude McCurdy
      - Hubbard, Henry M.
      - Hubbard, Paul
      - Jones, Nellie K.
      - Marsh, Charles
      - Marsh, Elias J., Jr.
      - Marsh, Matilda L.
      - Marsh, Robert McCurdy
      - Marsh, Sarah L. McCurdy
      - McCurdy, Caroline
      - McCurdy, George W.
      - McCurdy, Georgianna
      - McCurdy, Roberta W.
      - McCurdy, Susan
      - McCurdy, William F.
      - Pillot, Clara
      - Salisbury, Evelyn McCurdy
      - Symonds, Katie I.
      - Wagner, Sarah Griswold
      - Unidentified
    - General correspondence
      - Adler, Cyrus
      - Burbank, Luther
      - Deland, Fred
      - Freer, Charles Lang For additional material see Container 286, Freer Gallery of Art
      - Kennan, Caroline ("Lena")
      - Langley, Samuel P.
      - Raymond, George Lansing
      - Rubin, Hi
      - Tarbell, Ida M.
      - True, Mary H.
      - Miscellaneous, A-Z, (2 folders) (Box 74)
      - Unidentified
      - Letters of condolence on death of Alexander Graham Bell
    - Article file
      - "Notes on Alexander Graham Bell"
    - Miscellany
      - Wedding invitations, clippings, etc.
  - Fairchild, Nancy Bell
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Alexander Graham
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard
  - Grossman, Gertrude Hubbard
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Alexander Graham
      - Hubbard, Gertrude McCurdy
      - Salisbury, Evelyn McCurdy
      - Scudder, Alice H.
  - Grossman, Maurice N.
  - Grosvenor, Carol
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard
  - Grosvenor, Edwin A.
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Alexander Graham
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard
      - Grosvenor, Gilbert Hovey
  - Grosvenor, Edwin Prescott
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Alexander Graham
    - General correspondence
  - Grosvenor, Elsie Bell
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Alexander Graham, (2 folders)
      - Bell, Alexander Melville
      - Bell, Eliza Symonds (Box 75)
      - Bell, Helen A.
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard
        - 1888-1910, (9 folders)
        - 1911-1922, n.d., (5 folders) (Box 76)
      - Fairchild, Marian ("Daisy")
      - Grosvenor, Asa W.
      - Grosvenor, Gertrude
      - Grosvenor, Gilbert Hovey, (2 folders)
      - Grosvenor, Melville Bell
      - Hubbard, Edith
      - Hubbard, Gardiner Greene
      - Hubbard, Gertrude McCurdy
      - Symonds, Katie I.
      - Symonds, Mary
    - General correspondence
      - Thompson, Charles For additional material see Container 64, Death of Alexander Graham Bell
      - Miscellaneous, A-Z (Box 77)
      - Letters on death of Mabel Gardiner Hubbard Bell, 1923
    - Subject file
      - Centenary of Alexander Graham Bell's birth
      - Wedding
    - Article file
      - re film Alexander Graham Bell
      - "The Golden Rule"
      - "Memories of My Father"
      - "Notes on Dr. Alexander Graham Bell"
      - "Our Houseboat"
      - "The Unitarian Controversy"
    - Speech file
      - "Memories of My Father"
      - Untitled
        - 1944, Mar. 10, to the Eistophos Club
        - 1951, 1957, n.d.
    - Miscellany
      - Biographical material
      - Drawings, notes, printed matter
      - Financial papers
  - Grosvenor, Gertrude
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Alexander Graham
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard
  - Grosvenor, Gilbert Hovey (Box 78)
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Alexander Graham, (2 folders)
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard
        - 1900-1919, (7 folders)
        - 1920-1922, n.d., (3 folders) (Box 79)
      - Fairchild, David
      - Fairchild, Marian ("Daisy")
      - Grosvenor, Elsie Bell
      - Grosvenor, Gertrude H.
      - Grosvenor, Mabel
      - Grosvenor, Melville Bell
      - Hubbard, Gertrude McCurdy
      - Hubbard, William H.
      - Symonds, Herbert H.
      - Symonds, Maggie L.
    - General correspondence
      - Abbott, Charles
      - Baldwin, Frederick W. ("Casey")
      - Booth, Frank W. For additional material see Container 127, American Association to Promote the Teaching of Speech to the Deaf; Container 179, Census; Container 191, Institution for the Deaf and Dumb; and Container 201, Teachers of the deaf
      - Carty, John J. For additional material see Container 64, Death of Alexander Graham Bell
      - Clarke School for the Deaf, Northampton, Mass.
      - Crouter, Albert L. E.
      - Deland, Fred, 1912-1926, (2 folders) For additional material see Containers 81-83, Biography of Alexander Graham Bell
      - Fuller, Sarah For additional material see Containers 81-83, Biography of Alexander Graham Bell
      - Gregory, Ernest
      - Kelvin, William Thomson, Baron For additional material see Containers 81-83, Biography of Alexander Graham Bell
      - McClure, Samuel S. For additional material see Container 65, Dissolution of Montessori Educational Association, and Container 267, National Geographic Magazine
      - McKenzie, Catherine (Box 80)
      - National Geographic Society
      - Noyes, Frederick K.
      - Payne, John Barton
      - Shaw, Albert
      - Spicer-Simson, Theodore
      - Taylor, Harris
      - Ulke, Titus
      - Walcott, Charles D.
      - Watson, Thomas A.
      - Wright, Orville
      - Miscellaneous, A-W, and unidentified, (7 folders)
    - Subject file (Box 81)
      - Biography of Alexander Graham Bell, (14 folders); (15 folders); (20 folders) (Box 82, Box 83)
      - Montessori Educational Association, (2 folders) (Box 84)
    - Article file
      - "Alexander Graham Bell's Contribution to the
        - National Geographic Society"
      - "Biography of Alexander Graham Bell"
      - "The Electric Speaking Telephone and Other
        - Inventions of Alexander Graham Bell"
      - "The Tetrahedral Kites of Dr. Alexander Graham Bell"
      - "Notes Concerning Wishes of Mabel Hubbard Bell"
    - Miscellany
      - Biographical sketch of Gilbert Hovey Grosvenor
  - Grosvenor, Gloria
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard
  - Grosvenor, Lilian Waters (Mrs. Edwin A. Grosvenor)
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard
      - Grosvenor, Edwin Prescott
      - Grosvenor, Elsie Bell
  - Grosvenor, Mabel
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Alexander Graham
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard
  - Grosvenor, Mary A.
  - Grosvenor, Melville Bell
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Alexander Graham
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard
      - Fairchild, David
      - Fairchild, Marian ("Daisy")
      - Grosvenor, Elsie Bell
    - General correspondence, A-Z
  - Home, Noel C. M.
  - Home, Richard H., (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 85)
  - Home, Sophie C.
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Alexander Graham
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard
    - Article file
      - Untitled, n.d.
  - Hubbard, Adelaide
  - Hubbard, Charles Eustis
  - Hubbard, Gardiner Greene
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Alexander Graham
        - 1874-1878, (7 folders)
        - 1878-1893, (17 folders) (Box 86)
        - 1894-1897, 1906, n.d., (6 folders) (Box 87)
      - Bell, Grace Hubbard
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard
        - 1871-1897, n.d., (7 folders)
        - Fragments
      - Greene, Gardiner
      - Grossmann, Gertrude Hubbard
      - Grosvenor, Edwin A.
      - Hubbard, Gertrude McCurdy
        - 1870-1876
        - 1877-1892, n.d., (5 folders) (Box 88)
      - Hubbard, William
      - McCurdy, Richard
      - Scudder, Samuel H. For additional material see Container 271, Science
    - General correspondence
      - Flagg, Ernest
      - Grant, Ulysses S. For additional material see Containers 12-14, Visible speech
      - McCurdy, W. F.
      - Scott, Adam
      - True, Mary H.
      - Twain, Mark
      - Miscellaneous, A-W, and unidentified, (3 folders)
    - Article file (Box 89)
      - "The Education of Deaf Mutes"
      - "The Japanese Nation--A Typical Product of
        - Environment"
      - "Our Post Office"
    - Articles and speeches
    - Book file
      - The Education of Deaf Mutes: Shall It Be by Signs or Articulation?
      - The Story of the Rise of the Oral Method in America
    - Miscellany
      - Airplane design
      - Biographical material
      - Bookplates, indentures, notes, receipts, etc.
      - Degrees and certificates (Box 90)
      - International Bell Telephone Co.
      - Memorials and memorial services, 1898
      - Oil lands, Cape Breton, Nova Scotia, Canada
      - Postal telegraph system, (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box 91)
      - Printed matter, (1 folder) (Box 92)
      - Steamship papers
  - Hubbard, Gertrude McCurdy
    - Letterbook, 1846-1871
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Alexander Graham, (3 folders)
      - Bell, Charles James
      - Bell, Eliza Symonds
      - Bell, Grace Hubbard
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard (Box 93)
        - 1871-1882, (9 folders)
        - 1883-1895, (10 folders) (Box 94)
        - 1895-1913, n.d., (13 folders) (Box 95)
        - Undated, (6 folders) (Box 96)
      - Greene, Gardiner
      - Greene, May
      - Grossmann, Gertrude Hubbard
      - Grosvenor, Edwin A.
      - Hubbard, Eustis
      - Hubbard, Gardiner Greene
        - 1872-1877, (4 folders)
        - 1879-1886, n.d., (6 folders) (Box 97)
      - Marsh, Sara L. McCurdy
      - Mayer, Henry C.
      - McCurdy Evelyn
      - McCurdy, Gertrude Mercer Lee
      - McCurdy, Richard
      - McCurdy, Robert H.
      - McCurdy, Theodore
      - McCurdy, Theodore F.
      - Pillot, Gertrude H. ("Gipsy")
      - Ripley, Helen Bell
      - Salisbury, Evelyn McCurdy
      - Scudder, Samuel H. For additional material see Container 271, Science
      - Unidentified
    - General correspondence
      - Hale, Edward Everett
      - Hale, Ellen Day (Mrs. Edward Everett Hale)
      - True, Mary H.
      - Miscellaneous, A-Z, (3 folders)
    - Subject file (Box 98)
      - Dürer, Albrecht, engravings presented to the Library of Congress
    - Miscellany
      - Address books, (3 folders)
      - Legal papers (Box 99)
      - Obituary
      - Printed matter
      - Receipts and lists
  - Hubbard, Harry M.
  - Hubbard, James M.
  - Hubbard, Jane
  - Hubbard, John Parkinson
  - Hubbard, Mary Ann
  - Hubbard, Roberta
    - Family correspondence
      - Grossmann, Gertrude Hubbard
  - Hubbard, Samuel
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard
    - Miscellany
      - Memorial
  - Hubbard, Susan C. W.
  - Hubbard, William H.
  - Jones, Lilian Grosvenor
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard
    - Miscellany
  - Jordan, Emily
  - Kennedy, Eliza Grace Bell
  - Kerr, James
  - Leplastrier, Frances Symonds
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard
      - Fairchild, Marian ("Daisy")
      - Miscellaneous
  - Marsh, Elias J.
  - Marsh, Elias J., Jr.
  - Marsh, Roberta
  - Marsh, Sarah Griswold
  - Marston, Nancy Bates
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard
  - McCurdy, Caroline
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard
      - Fairchild, Marian ("Daisy")
      - Other family members
  - McCurdy, Charles Johnson
  - McCurdy, Gertrude Mercer Lee (Box 100)
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Grace Hubbard
      - Grossmann, Gertrude Hubbard
      - Hubbard, Gertrude McCurdy, (2 folders)
  - McCurdy, Mabel B.
  - McCurdy, Robert H.
    - Diary, ca. 1834
    - Family correspondence
      - Hubbard, Gardiner Greene
      - Hubbard, Gertrude McCurdy
    - Miscellany
      - Biographical material, financial papers, and
        - printed matter
      - Scrapbook, 1883
  - McCurdy, Roberta
  - McCurdy, Theodore F.
    - Family correspondence
      - Hubbard, Gertrude McCurdy
  - McCurdy genealogy, (2 folders)
  - Milne, Elizabeth B. Symonds (Box 101)
    - Family correspondence
      - Symonds, Edith L.
  - Pillot, Gertrude H. ("Gipsy")
  - Ripley, Helen Bell
  - Symonds, Bessie
  - Symonds, C. Edward
  - Symonds, Charles H.
    - Family correspondence
      - Symonds, James W.
  - Symonds, Edith L.
  - Symonds, Edward S.
  - Symonds, Herbert H.
  - Symonds, Hetty J.
  - Symonds, James W.
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Alexander Graham
    - Poetry file
  - Symonds, Katie I.
  - Symonds, Louisa
  - Symonds, Mary E.
    - Family correspondence
      - Bell, Alexander Graham
      - Bell, Mabel Gardiner Hubbard
      - Symonds, James W.
    - Miscellany
      - Addresses, 1848-1853, (2 folders)
      - Poem
  - Symonds, Nella
  - Symonds, Samuel
  - Unidentified
- General Correspondence, 1870-1922, n.d. (Box 102-142)
  Letterbooks, notebooks, and letters sent and received by Alexander Graham Bell. Some letterbooks include notes, papers, and other writings by Bell as well as correspondence.
  The letterbooks and notebooks are arranged chronologically. The remaining correspondence is arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - Letterbooks (Box 102)
    - Index, 1879-1880
    - 1880-1883, (2 vols.)
    - 1883-1886, (2 vols.) (Box 103)
    - 1886-1890, (3 vols.) (Box 104)
    - 1890-1894, (6 vols.) (Box 105)
    - 1894-1896, (2 vols.) (Box 106)
    - 1896-1897, (2 vols.) (Box 107)
    - 1896-1913, (2 vols.) (Box 108)
    - 1897-1898, (2 vols.) (Box 109)
    - 1898-1899, (2 vols.) (Box 110)
    - 1899 (Box 111)
    - 1900-1901, (3 vols.) (Box 112)
    - 1900-1902, (3 vols.) (Box 113)
    - 1901-1907, (3 vols.) (Box 114)
    - 1902-1904, (2 vols.) (Box 115)
    - 1902-1905, (3 vols.) (Box 116)
    - 1903-1913, (2 vols.) (Box 117)
    - 1905-1909, (3 vols.) (Box 118)
    - 1906-1908, (3 vols.) (Box 119)
    - 1906-1912, (3 vols.) (Box 120)
    - 1908-1911, (3 vols.) (Box 121)
    - 1912-1916, (2 vols.) (Box 122)
    - 1912-1921, (2 vols.) (Box 123)
    - 1916-1917, (3 vols.) (Box 124)
    - 1917-1919, (2 vols.) (Box 125)
    - 1921-1922, (2 vols.) (Box 126)
  - Alphabetical file (Box 127)
    - "A-Az" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Abbe, Cleveland For additional material see Containers 326-327, Wednesday evening receptions
    - Aberdeen and Temair, John Campbell Gordon, First Marquis of
    - Adams, Charles K.
    - Adler, Cyrus
    - Albert I, Prince of Monaco
    - Alden, Henry M.
    - American Association to Promote the Teaching of Speech to the Deaf, 1897-1902, n.d., (2 folders)
    - Anagnos, Michael
    - Anthony, William A.
    - Austin, Oscar P.
    - Ayres, Brown